

 \searrow

keshavsoni95@gmail.com

8901272767

0

Gurgaon, India

in

linkedin.com/in/keshavsoni95

SKILLS

Javascript

NodeJs

PostgreSQL

Kafka

PL/SQL

Git

Redis

Asp .Net

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

Full Professional Proficiency

HIND

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Reading

Travelling

Cricket

Keshav Soni

Software Engineer

Resourceful Engineer with around 4 years of experience in building scalable web applications. Excellent problem-solving skills, enthusiastic about learning new technologies and design efficient systems. Looking forward to work with a progressive team that utilizes my skills to the best of use.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer RSG Media Systems

02/2020 - Present Gurgaon, India

Centralized rights and deal management system to streamline royalty processing

Roles and Responsibilities

- Creating from scratch the company's flagship product using NodeJs and Postgres to improve performance and making it lightweight and scalable. The product was earlier in Asp.Net and Oracle. Decreasing the load and wait time by 80%.
- Created and optimized apis to process sensitive financial data of huge clients like NBA,NBCU, NFL, Mattel etc.
- Good functional knowledge of both media and finance domain.
- Performed code reviews and peer programming resulting in a 30% increase in overall productivity.
- Been a part of technical solution discussions with the architects each time a new development has been introduced.
- Working in a fast paced environment with focus on both enhancements in the product as well as ensuring client's needs are catered.

Software Engineer Sopra Steria

11/2017 - 02/2020 Noida, India

Roles and Responsibilities

- Worked on ASP.NET web application and built an ASP.NET WEB API application from the scratch with the team.
- Versed in complete software life cycle from preliminary needs analysis to enterprise-wide deployment through continuous development kit and support.
- Worked as a key techno-functional team member in an agile project which involved direct interaction with the client.
- Wrote efficient code as well as functional solution documents.
- Responsible for ensuring correct and timely delivery of code using Jenkins.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of TechnologyPDM College of Engineering

2013 - 2017

Specialization

Computer Science

 6 months internship on Microsoft Dynamics NAV

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Strong communication skills. Hence, the ability to handle international clients well.

Highly motivated individual and good team player with good record of mentoring juniors.

Won SPOT and Pinnacle Award and appreciation from CEO for quick reactivity and dedication towards complex production issues and understanding the business very well.

Visited client in France for discussion and maturation of complex User Stories and received accolades for good work in critical areas of application